My name is Aaron. Um, this is actually
real real background. I'm in New York
City. Uh, it's not a background filter.
And I pastor a church. Uh, I planted it,
uh, in 2014.
So, we're almost 11 years old. And um
we've been called everything from
Excalibur to Xbox to even exotic, but
our church's name is called Exilic and
we're just about five six blocks south
of Time Square. Um so that's me. If you
if you open up the uh slides, we're
going to be taking a look at the topic
of engaging and reaching our culture
specifically through
uh presiding and preaching. Uh
discipleship we'll get into a little
bit, but it's going to be mostly through
uh presiding and preaching. Okay. So, um
so we'll be taking a look at engaging
and uh reaching our culture through
presiding and preaching. Um yeah, so our
church our church is uh 11 years old,
almost 11 years old. We are a scratch
plant. We we started with five people.
Um and then it slowly grew. Um it first
began with a book club uh back in 2014
when the reason for God had come out and
so a lot of skeptics were coming out to
it and we were meeting once a month and
then I thought it'd be cool if more of
these conversations took place. And so,
uh, we launched a church at the end of
2014. And so, our church has always had
a huge heart for skeptics, uh,
especially in New York City. And so,
when we first started, um, we were
probably around 30% unchurched and
dechurched.
Uh, and our church has slowly grown. Uh,
we're probably, that number has dropped
down. We're probably at around like 10%
now, which we're still really happy
about. uh and we don't want to dip below
10% if possible. Uh our first convert
had never gone to church before in his
life, was in his early 30s, uh was a
seale guy. Our first convert is now one
of our first elders and uh he is now
married to my wife's cousins. So we're
like family family and he's he's on our
elder board now. He didn't know how to
pray. he would actually introduce
himself to God every time he prayed. Um,
and so the fact that he is now an elder
is is pretty awesome. And those are some
of the stories we've seen. And so we
just wanted to share a little bit about
some of the stuff that we have done uh
in our own churches community. And if
it's helpful to you, hopefully you can
uh implement some of that stuff too. Uh
I want to just look at four things for
today. Uh the first one is why talk
about the topic of engaging and reaching
our culture. So the big why. Number two,
what's happening in our cultural moment?
Number three, how do we engage and reach
our culture specifically through our
presiding and preaching, which is
something that you already do. And then
number four, there'll be some time for
Q&A as well. All right. So, let's talk
about this topic. Why why talk about it?
Uh, if you look at number six, slide
number six says, um, a lot of our
churches are ingrown and not skeptic
friendly.
we don't know how to engage and reach
our culture well and presiding and
preaching at own on hard times. So those
are some of the negatives. Uh but there
are some positives and that is your
churches can become skeptic friendly and
not ingrown. As pastors you can engage
and reach a culture through something
you already do which is presiding and
preaching. And number three hopefully
you walk away from this conversation
thinking that you can do this. This is
not just for the tinkers of the world.
This is something you can do. Okay. So,
what are some things that are happening
in our cultural moment right now? Uh I
would say three things, maybe three and
a half. Uh the first is that we live in
a I'm using all these uh in a
disenchanted culture and so we're a
little bit less helpful than before.
We're distracted which leads to more
superficial thinking. Obviously, a lot
of disunityity, outrage, and
polarization outside the church and
inside the church. And number four is
one that I I've kind of recently crossed
out. I think in the past 15, 20 years,
Christianity has always been seen as
something that was dangerous. Um, it's
not just dumb, but it's also a threat.
Um, my sense is that it's not as much
like that anymore. In the past, it was
not just implausible, but immoral. But I
feel like there's a cultural tide that's
shifting with regards to the fourth one.
So I just struck that out. So just to
flesh that out in a little bit more
detail, if you take a look at slide
number 10, some of the reasons why we're
disenchanted, less hopeful, there's
wars, pandemics, racial injustice,
political division,
uh the future of our economy, global
warming, environmental issues. We're
collectively all suffering from mental
health and AI. Like who knows what this
is going to do to change the cultural
landscape and people. So, we certainly
live in a disenchanting culture. We're
also more distracted than ever before.
Uh, it's hard to think deeply because
our attention span is low. And so, uh,
supposedly, I don't know how true this
is, Microsoft did a study years ago
where they did something um, where they
discovered that the attention span of
goldfish are 9 seconds and the attention
span of humans is 8 seconds. And so, we
now have an attention span lower than
goldfish. So think about your attention
span like a glowing ball.
Every 8 seconds your attention span is
going from one thing to another. Voom
here to voom there. Every 8 seconds it's
bouncing around. And when that's the
case, it's really hard to think deeply
into certain truths about life. So we're
distracted. Part of that is technology,
social media, entertainment. There's
also a lot more disunityity fracturing
in our culture than ever before. whether
it's stuff on mass, vaccines, race,
politics, religion, and there's
certainly even in-house disunityity even
within the church. And then the one that
I crossed out in slide 13 is that
uh in the past, Christianity was not
just as dumb, but dangerous. Not just
implausible, but immoral, bigoted,
divisive, and harmful. Um some examples
are things like Christian nationalism.
Uh Christians are sexually bigoted,
hateful to certain groups. It's unjust.
so on and so forth. But I do think that
in our cultural moment, things are
slowly starting to change from there.
And here are some examples uh of why I
think that's the case. And so if you
take a look at slide 14, a friend of
mine started a group called 4NYC in
partnership with Bara and Glue. This
study came out, I want to say in early
May, so it's only about three or four
months old. Uh in New York City at
least, Christianity is growing. The
proportion of residents identifying as
Christian increased from 58% in 2022 to
62% in 2025.
This growth is notably driven by Gen Z
with 71% identifying as Christian in
2025. A significant rise from 56% just
three years ago. Furthermore, 23% of Gen
Z in New York City now qualify as
practicing Christians, up from 10% in
2022.
Perceptions are also on the rise as
well. Positive perceptions of local
churches are rising across New York
City. The combined 82% of all residents
report a favorable view, very or
somewhat favorable in 2025. Even among
unchurched, 76% hold favorable views.
And so if if Christianity were a threat
or dangerous, we wouldn't see
Christianity increasing and perceptions
of the church being favorable the way
that we're seeing it today. Hence uh me
saying that I think some of the the
cultural tide is changing. Some reasons
for this change in slide 16.
Um,
in 2001 when 9/11 happened,
uh, which I think was on a Tuesday,
uh, for those of you who know the story
of Redeemer,
uh, I think they almost doubled in size
overnight, that following Sunday. And so
there was a
sort of a an immediate
uh, influx of people that were
investigating Christianity.
Uh, one of the things that Keller would
say is that co we're sort of
experiencing the same amount of trauma,
but uh, the results are going to be a
little bit more delayed. And I think
we're finally starting to see the delays
happening now. Uh, where people are
getting more and more interested with
Christianity and are asking more
existential questions. And so, and part
of the reason for that is I think a
dystopian, distracted, disunified life
is not exactly appealing.
That's not exactly a salivating thing.
Additionally, cultural influencers,
Christian and non-Christian, are
favorably talking about Christianity,
whether it's Joe Rogan, Jordan Peterson,
Andrew Schultz, um, and the list goes
George Stanto, the list goes on and on.
So, the pendulum is sort of re reacting
hard from a failed experiment of new
atheism, secularism, liberalism,
particularly amongst young men. And
while 71% of Gen Z identify as
Christian, what's also interesting is
that most of them are men and not women.
And what's also interesting is that most
of these young men lean politically
right while most women lean politically
left. But that's a that's a conversation
for another time. Having said that, that
is going to have an impact on the church
uh as well.
All right. And so these are some of the
I just wanted to get into a little bit
of what's happening in our culture
before we talk about how to reach our
culture.
Uh, and if we're going to be serious
about reaching the cultural moment that
we're in, we sort of have to be like the
men of Ishachar in 1 Chronicles 12:32.
If you look at slide 18, from Ishakar,
men who understood the times and knew
what Israel should do.
And so, as pastors in particular, we
have to be like the menar
who understand the cultural moment that
we're in. that we not only learn know
how to execute scripture but we know how
to execute the cultural tides that we're
in and we know what we ought to do as
well. So what are some things that we
need to do? Uh we need to understand and
we need to do. I would say a few things.
Uh the first is that God is moving.
Uh he's moving in particular with the
with the next generation. I do think
that we have to steward what God is
doing well. the movement that is taking
place by continuing to engage in
retraculture. And while individual faith
has increased rapidly, it doesn't
necessarily mean that church attendance
and quality formation uh has increased
at the same pace. And so that's
something uh to keep in mind. New
atheism and relativism and things like
that sort of felt like a flash in the
pan. And so it does seem like there is a
pendulum swing that is taking place as
to why Christianity in particular has
been a little bit more appealing than
before.
And again in the future the pendulum
swing back again to the other end too.
But right now we're seeing it swing in a
favorable way towards Christianity.
So how do we then engage and reach our
culture as pastors? And there are two
things that I want to talk about because
there's multiple ways of engaging and
reaching our culture. But the two things
I want to talk about is presiding and
preaching which you already do,
right? And which you're already good at.
So this is not something that you have
to add a lot more to your arsenal than
than what you already do. So the
question is how do we engage and reach
our culture through our presiding first?
Now this is this is something that I'm
pretty passionate about because I'm
guessing when you went to seminary you
read a lot of books on preaching and how
to preach well. My guess is that not one
person here has ever read a book on
presiding though. And presiding is just
as important as preaching because you're
leading people uh uh through the liturgy
in in worship. And as you lead people
through worship, you actually have an
opportunity to engage and reach uh our
culture as well, even through your
presiding. And so this is just a sample
from our church's liturgy. Uh on slide
23, it looks like your typical
PCA liturgy. There's a call to worship,
songs, affirmation of faith, uh,
confession and pardon. We sing again,
announcement, sermon, offering, song,
and benediction. It's your typical
sermon outline. But one of the things
that we do just to be as secret
sensitive as possible, particularly for
those who have never gone to church
before, is that we put the entire order
of liturgy on one slide. So, it's
actually on every slide, and there's a
ticker that tells people where we are in
the order of service. And so if you go
to a Broadway show here in New York,
you'll get a program and it'll outline
where you are in the program. There'll
be an intermission and then you'll know
what what scene or act is next and when
when the conclusion happens. And if
you've never been to church before, I
mean, you're sort of at the mercy of
whatever is happening. You know, you you
don't you don't know where you are in
the service. And so, one of the things
that we do to be seeker friendly is to u
list the entire order of liturgy on
every single slide. I remember there was
actually one person
uh who had never been to church before
um in their lives and
uh what was interesting is that the
first comment that they made was it had
nothing to do with the music or how
great the sermon was but the first thing
that they said was they pointed at our
screen and they said don't ever get rid
of that. It was because of that I felt a
little bit more peaceful about where we
were going with the service. And so
that's something that we do. The second
thing that we do is that um with each
element of our liturgy, we try to take
about a minute to explain it so that
people know what a call to worship is.
If you don't do that, then it's hard to
kind of know what you're participating
in. And so, you know, a lot of churches
have their Sunday services online now.
And one of the things that I'll see
sometimes is people say things like,
"Hey, good morning. Welcome to Exilic.
We're so glad you're here. Please stand
for the call to worship." And there's
this sort of presupposition that you
even know what a call to worship is. And
so, one of the things that we try to do
is that again, we try to give a one
minute explanation in a seeker sensitive
way about what a call to worship is. And
so I'll give you an example. I'll try to
give you an example of each of these. So
for example, I'll say something like,
"Good morning. My name is Aaron. Welcome
to Exilic. Uh every Sunday we have uh
something called the call to worship."
And basically we're using this time to
enter into the presence of God because
he invites us there. So one way of
understanding what is taking place is
something like this. So I'll I'll use an
example like um the
the old English word for worship
is worth. In other words, we all worship
whatever we think is worthy. The reason
why we're gathered here on Sunday
morning is because we believe no one is
more worthy of our worship than God. Uh
not our money, our portfolios, our
following. No one is more worthy of our
worship, not even our kids, than God. He
is the one that is most worthy of all
things. Uh please stand with me as we uh
worship and sing to God. So that's one
example of a how to introduce uh call to
worship in a secret sensitive way. Uh,
another example is our affirmation of
faith and sometimes we'll do the
apostles creed, we'll do the nine creed,
we'll do Colossians 1, Ephesians 2,
uh, something from the confessions and
one way of talking about or introducing
our affirmation of faith is something
like this. Um, have you ever gotten a
Hallmark card before for your birthday
or for Christmas? Whoever sent you that
Hallmark card didn't write those words.
someone else wrote those words but they
wanted you to know that they mean those
words too. That's also how they feel.
Those are also their convictions.
And similarly like we didn't we didn't
write these words of the apostles creed
or or the nine creed. There were other
people that did it but we also believe
and affirm these words. Uh that's an
example of doing it. or um sometimes
people come to our church and there's a
lot of standing and sitting and saying
things in unison. It almost feels like
an episode of 1984. feels very Orwellian
and sometimes it sounds weird and so
I'll say something like um I was at my
daughter's Friday
um uh assembly for their school and one
of the things that they did was they
asked everyone to stand to say the
pledge of allegiance and in unison
everyone put their hands over their
hearts and said I pledge allegiance to
the flag and similarly we're doing the
same as we stand together and say this
uh say what we're about to say in
unison, we're declaring together what it
is that we believe. So, these are all
ways of sort of normalizing uh what
we're doing. Confession uh and pardon is
a time of repentance. And so, I'll say
something like, "Have you ever gotten on
the wrong subway before? You're going
south instead of north. What do you have
to do? You have to get off the train
that's going south in order to turn and
go a different direction." And
sometimes, some of us, we walk, all of
us walk
uh uh go astray. We go in a direction
that we're not supposed to go in. And
during this time, it's an opportunity
for us to sort of recalibrate our hearts
and to go in the right direction. Or
I'll tell a story like there was once a
college freshman who never done laundry
before. He went into his basement, took
out his dirty XL sweater, put all the
other dirty clothes on top of the XL
sweater, folded it up into a ball, threw
it in the wash, and then when he popped
it out, he realized that all of his
clothes were still dirty. During a time
of confession and repentance, what we're
doing is we're opening up our hearts so
God can clean all the dirty laundry that
is in our hearts. So, let's open up our
hearts to God and simply say, "I'm
sorry." It's a safe space to say that.
So, these are all examples of ways that
we try to introduce our uh our liturgy
to our people. And these are all ways of
doing like 30 to to one minute sermons.
Now, one of the things I would love to
see, uh, if you have the bandwidth for,
because I haven't seen it, is for
someone to write a book on presiding,
and just to have a hundred examples on
how to do a call to worship, to have a
hundred examples on how to lead people
through songs, 100 examples on
affirmation of faith, 100 examples on
confession and pardon, 100 examples on
how to tithe well, 100 examples on how
to introduce a benediction. what that is
that that resource could be so good for
the church because everyone has a
liturgy. Every denomination has a
liturgy. Some are more high church, some
are more low church, but for me it's an
opportunity
to really engage those that are
unfamiliar with the faith, not just the
sermon. And all it takes is 30 seconds
if it's really really good. And so I I
have a I probably have a 100 pages worth
of notes. It's just all discombobulated.
But if one of you wants to tackle on
that project, it could be a massive gift
to the church. There's zero books on
presiding that I know of. Um there's one
that kind of does it on repentance but
not on the whole liturgy. But if you one
of you wanted to tackle it, that could
be a great project to tackle on. Uh so
slide number 24, five questions for you
to reflect on. Usually I do breakout
groups for this but for time sake
after this call is over just want you to
reflect on these five questions. What is
your liturgy like? How do you lead your
congregation through your liturgy? Are
there are there hidden presuppositions
there? Is it mostly for believers? Are
you acknowledging the presence of
unbelievers? In all honesty, if a
skeptic was visiting your church for the
first time, how do you think they would
experience your liturgy? What is one
thing you would change to make it more
skeptic friendly? And how much do you
incorporate stories and illustrations in
your presiding?
Okay, so we I think we need to put maybe
not the same amount of effort as our
preaching, but I would say a good amount
of effort into our presiding and not
just our preaching.
So that's one way of reaching out to
those um that are unfamiliar with Jesus
is through your presiding. So just want
you to really reflect on what you do on
a Sunday to Sunday basis and how you can
engage skeptics better. Okay, let me
jump to the preaching. Okay, 25 slide
25. How do we engage and reach our
culture through our preaching? So if you
I'm assuming most of you have read uh
gauging upon the audience in this room
uh recent for uh 10 years ago. If you
remember some of the chapters there,
chapter one, there can't be just one
religion. Chapter four, the church is
responsible for injustice. Five, loving
God will not send people to hell. Six,
science has disproved Christianity.
Seven, you can't take the Bible
literally. I mean, if you if you've
actually talked with Tim, one of the
things that he'll say is that that book
was actually more for Christians that
sort of struggle with fiism or an easy
belieism than it was for non-believers.
These are the questions that really
Christians have. And so our culture, he
would say, is not even thinking about it
or asking these types of questions. And
so that's why he wrote making sense of
God in slide 28, which he thought should
have been a prequil to the reason for
God. And so if you look at the contents
in making sense of God, they're very
different from the reason for God. And
so chapter three, it's all about
meaning. Uh chapter four, it's all about
satisfaction. Chapter five, freedom. Uh
seven, identity. Eight, hope, nine,
morals. Um, if I can if I can just say
this, at least for me, there is not one
sermon where I don't talk about one of
these issues.
Every single sermon has some component
of either freedom, identity, hope,
satisfaction. Almost, not almost, every
single sermon talks about these things.
Um,
um, and I I'll just I'll share I think
the best medium for them is actually via
stories. So, I'll just give you a couple
examples of of them really uh really
quickly. So, with freedom,
um imagine you're you're finding Nemo.
You're trapped in a goldfish bowl and
you want freedom. You don't want to live
in this bowl anymore. And so, you ram
into the bowl and the bowl wobbles. You
ran into the bowl and the bowl wobbles
again. You ram into the bowl and the
bowl tips over and now you're free.
Except you're not. you're solely dying
because you were never meant to live in
that context. You were always meant to
live in this context. And so freedom
isn't the absence of restraints. It's
the presence of the right restraint.
Right? You've all you've all heard
similar stories or analogies to that.
Like that's an that's a great example of
talking about freedom in Christ and how
it's not a straight jacket. I'll give
you an example for identity.
Um there was a movie that came out like
10 years ago called Unknown. There's two
movies called Unknown. One of them is
even more unknown than the other. Um,
but bunch of guys wake up in a chemical
warehouse. I think five guys wake up in
a chemical warehouse with amnesia. The
chemicals sort of knock them out. They
do find out that three of them are
criminals, two of them are cops, but no
one knows who's a criminal or a cop.
They get a phone call from the other
criminals saying they're coming. And so
they hang up. And now they're all
freaking out because the criminals are
coming, but inside the chemical
warehouse, no one knows who's who's a
cop and who's a criminal. And finally,
one of them says, "Well, how am I
supposed to know how to act if I don't
even know who I am?"
That's an identity question, right? You
don't know how to act unless you first
know who you are. And so that's a again
a tight illustration or story to talk
about how it's important to know who you
really really are. And that is a child
of God. a beloved son and daughter of
God. Another example, this is legend
about Augustine who had um who struggle
struggled a lot with sexual promiscuity.
There's one one day he's shopping at
Trader Joe's. He's at an aisle. One of
his mistresses sees him and she goes,
"Augustine, it is I." He sees her and
he's like, "Oh my gosh, I can't believe
it's her." So he walks to another aisle
to kind of dodge her and she follows him
and and she's like, "Augustine, it is
I." And he's like, "Oh my gosh, this is
so embarrassing. I don't know what to
do." So he goes to the next aisle. She
follows him again and she goes,
"Augustine,
it is I." And Augustine, seeing that she
he could no longer dodge her, he turns
to her and says, "But it is no longer
I."
He had changed. He is not the same man
that he used to be. There's an identity
shift that has taken place and that's
the kind of identity shift that God
wants with all of us. Right? You are not
the same person that you used to be. The
old has come, the new has come. So those
are some examples of what you have to do
in every single sermon if you're really
serious about engaging uh and reaching
the gospel. Slide 29. What is cultural
apologetics?
Exit Jesus and apologetics. Jesus says
it himself. You have heard that it was
said. cultural zeitgeist philosophers of
the time but I say to you so this is
counterandic pieces that's what he's
doing here counter formation best medium
for this are parables as Jesus would do
or context stories Steve Jobs once said
the most powerful person in the room is
the storyteller so even if you think
about the LG LGBTQ movement one of the
reasons why this movement has uh become
so meteoric is because they are the best
storytellers to be frank and so Whoever
tells the best story usually wins. And
we serve a God that says in the
beginning uh he made the heavens and the
earth which is a story that ends with
revelation. And so God is the speak
speaking God who tells the best story of
all. And it's up to us to not jack up
telling this story. We have to tell it
as as as amazing and as beautiful as it
is. We have to do a good job of keeping
it that way. Right? So we can't do it in
justice. Uh so every sermon try to
tackle something from the meaning of God
or or making sense of God. I think the
other thing that's really important is
preaching spiritual formation and
counter formation.
Um I think there's a reason why
whether it's uh John Markr
um Pete Scazero, Rich Belotes, John
Tyson, um Tyler Stanton, those guys have
um filled in a void uh that has been
missing I think in our cultural moment.
And uh like every movement, there'll be
pros and cons which will become a little
bit clearer like a decade from now. But
I do think that positive speaking
they've really filled a massive void. Uh
this is what we call sanctification,
right? Um but the language that is
couched I think is a lot more helpful
for today. And so if you even look at
texts like Galatians 4:19, my ch
children with whom I am again in the
pains of childbirth until Christ is
formed in you. There's formation
language. Colossians 1. He is the one we
proclaim admonishing and teaching
everyone with all wisdom so that we may
present everyone fully mature in Christ.
Mark 12, he gives us the categories for
formation, right? Loving God with our
heart, soul, mind, and strength. And so
if you look at slide 32, our church's
mission is to inspire thinkers to
believe and inspire believers to think.
Just a New York City way of talking
about the great commission. Uh inspiring
thinkers to believe is conversion.
inspiring believers to think is
sanctification maturation. So this is
just a New York City way of talking
about the great commission. And if I was
in Alabama uh or Texas, it would be
something along the lines of cultural
Christianity. And you you might not be
Christian. You think you're Christian,
but you're not. And kind of on doing
that, if I was on the West Coast in LA,
I probably do something along the lines
of stories. But in New York City, this
works really well for us. Uh our vision.
So your mission is what you want to do.
Your vision is who you want to be. Our
vision as a church is to be fully formed
in Christ to embody his head, heart, and
hands. Uh and so those are the that's
the ven diagram that we use for full
formation. And so we have to preach
against counter formation because if we
don't, we end up being malformed and
deformed in our disciplehip.
And so um usually in our camp, the
reform camp we look a little bit like
Albert Einstein.
a lot lateral formation in the head but
not so much on the heart or hands and so
that leads to theological snobbery. Uh
other camps tend to focus too much on
the heart but not the head and the
hands. So that can lead to a kind of
pyotism, a 17th century pyotism. And
then the social gospel is heavy on the
hands uh but smaller in the heart and
and the head. And so we want to make
sure that we're practicing full
formation uh in the way that we do
disciplehip
uh to and to counter the formation that
is taking place. And so those two things
I think are really important in our
preaching uh the making sense of God
stuff and formation stuff in reaching
our culture. It resonates really really
well.
Um, just if this is helpful at all on
slide 35, what one of the things that we
did is we talked about the head, heart,
and hands for every single ministry to
make sure we're balanced. So, we're not
too head heavy, heart heavy, or hand
heavy. These are some of the ministries
that we had last year
uh because we're serious about forming
our people into the image of Christ more
and more. And so, if you want to do
something like this as a disciplehip
pathway exercise, that could be helpful.
Um, let's take a look at that. And let
me just close it with one story and then
we can have maybe 10 minutes for Q&A.
Um, I was talking with a skeptic in our
church
a few years ago and we had been talking
for a while and I said
we we had we had developed enough
relationship, Kevin. I said, "Bro, what
what is it going to take for you to be a
Christian? We've been talking forever.
What's it going to take?" and he he
actually um turned the tables on me and
he said, 'Well, Aaron, what would it
take for you not to be a Christian?
And I was like, "Huh, no one's ever
asked me that before." And I said, "You
could actually do two things for me to
recamp my faith." Number one, you could
find the missing body of Jesus. You
oceans 11, that thing, my faith is done,
right? Because he bodily rose again from
the dead, not just his soul. But I don't
think you're going to find it. But there
is a second thing that you can do that
would make me decon convert from
Christianity and it's this. Tell me a
better story.
You can tell me a better story than
this. I will My good news is not that
good anymore. It's just news. Tell me
something better. But evolution does not
cut it for me. I'm not like the idea
that I'm a sophisticated chimpanzeee
that can build Teslas and fly to the
moon doesn't do it for me. or nihilism
doesn't do it for me. Materialism
doesn't do it for me. Uh hedenism, it
doesn't do it for me. Tell me a better
story than Christianity and I'll
consider it.
A month later, he made a profession of
faith and was baptized. He's one of the
most active people in our church today.
And so, one of the things that we have
to do as preachers is to communicate how
great this news really is.
and
Whitfield, one of the things that he
did, and I don't know if it was Ben
Franklin or someone else, but they said
of Whitfield's preaching, I don't I
don't believe in what he's saying, but
he believes in it so much that he makes
me want to believe in it. And so, there
has to be this conviction, not just a
beauty in what we're saying, but a deep
conviction in the stories that we're
telling that will also help reach the
generation that we're in. Uh because
people are searching for answers. This
is our moment. The spirit is blowing. We
just got to set up the sale.
Uh and these are some tools that can
hopefully help you do that to our
presiding app and preaching what you
already